nintex.com 2019-05-29

# Privacy Policy - Nintex

## EU-U.S. Privacy Shield

Nintex participates in and has certified its compliance with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework. Nintex is committed to subjecting all personal data received from European Union (EU) member countries, in reliance on the Privacy Shield Framework, to the Framework’s applicable Principles. To learn more about the Privacy Shield Framework, visit the U.S. Department of Commerce’s [Privacy Shield List](https://www.privacyshield.gov/list).

Nintex is responsible under the Principles for the processing of Personal Data it receives under the Privacy Shield and subsequently transfers to third parties acting as agents on our behalf. Nintex remains liable if such agent processes Personal Data from the European Economic Area and/or Switzerland in a manner inconsistent with the Principles (unless Nintex can prove that we are not responsible for the event giving rise to the damage).

With respect to personal data received or transferred pursuant to the Privacy Shield Framework, Nintex is subject to the regulatory enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission. In certain situations, Nintex may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at <https://www.jamsadr.com/eu-us-privacy-shield>. Under certain conditions, more fully described on the [Privacy Shield website,](https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=How-to-Submit-a-Complaint) you may be entitled to invoke binding arbitration when other dispute resolution procedures have been exhausted.

## Swiss – U.S. Privacy Shield Framework

Nintex also complies with the Swiss – U.S. Privacy Shield framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal data from Switzerland. Nintex has certified to the Department of Commerce that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles. If there is any conflict between the terms in this privacy policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view Nintex’s certification, please visit <https://www.privacyshield.gov/>.

## Information Obtained by Nintex

**Personal information you provide:** We store the personal information you enter on the Nintex website or give to Nintex in other ways. We currently obtain personal information through:

  * registration to use our products and services;
  * event tracker scanning;
  * registration for events and webinars;
  * sign-up to our newsletters and event alerts; and
  * participation in discussion forums.

**Personal information currently solicited:** We collect first and last name, sign-in name, password, position, company name, contact phone number, country and email address.

**Uses made of collected personal information:** Nintex collects and logs this information in order to:

  * identify you when you sign-into your Nintex Connect account;
  * send you information you have requested, such as our newsletters and alerts;
  * carry out statistical analysis of the Nintex website and the people visiting, in order to improve the website and our services; and
  * contact you directly, or via one of our distribution partners, following the supply of personal information. If you wish to stop all Nintex correspondence please contact [inquiries@nintex.com](mailto:inquiries@nintex.com)

**Device Information:** When you download and use our Services, Nintex automatically collects information on the type of device you use and your operating system version.

**Geo-Location:** On devices that enable location-based services, we may receive location information (determined by GPS or other signals), if you consent. We may use this information to provide personalized location-based services and content. You can restrict our access to your device’s location by adjusting the location-based service preferences on your device.

## Automatic Collection – Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies

In common with most other websites, Nintex and its affiliates, analytics partners, marketing partners, or service providers use cookies and similar technologies to analyze trends and to manage your session on the Nintex website and Nintex Connect.

Tracking technologies are used to make your visits easier in several ways: necessary session management; performance enhancement; and functionality. Cookies and other similar technologies help manage your session so that you can move easily from one page to another, so that your page requests are loaded in a smooth, consistent, and secure manner, and to track user traffic patterns using statistics from users’ visits to the Nintex website. These technologies also make your next visit easier by authenticating sign-ins to the parts of the site that are for registered users, to enable you to submit forms or other information through the website, to initiate downloads of content, and otherwise store any preferences or selections you set through the website. Finally, these technologies make the site more useful. This remembered information helps us understand how people use the website and gives us explicit information about the technologies that we use and your choices when it comes to these technologies. As true of most websites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information may include internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and/or clickstream data. We do not link this automatically collected data to any other information we collect about you.t you.

Unless you have adjusted your browser settings so that it will refuse browser cookies, our system will issue browser cookies as soon as you visit one of our Services, and, once you have browser cookies enabled and visited one of our Services, we store a browser cookie on your computer or device to remember this for the next time you visit our Services. This Cookie will expire. However, if you wish to withdraw your consent before then, you may do so at any time, but will need to delete your browser cookies using your internet browser settings.

If you do not want to accept browser cookies, most browsers provide a simple procedure that allows you to configure your browser settings so that your browser automatically declines browser cookies, or gives you the choice of declining or accepting the transfer to your computer of a particular browser cookie from a particular Service. You can find instructions for disabling cookies on most browser types on AboutCookies.org’s “How to delete Cookies” page at [www.aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/) and at [www.youronlinechoices.eu](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/).

However, the use of Cookies may be necessary to provide certain features, and choosing to reject browser cookies may reduce the functionality of the Nintex site or services. If you disable essential Cookies, functions that will likewise be disabled include, among other things: the ability to log in, the ability to download materials and products, the ability to use single sign on to access the partner portals. If you disable non-essential Cookies, the site and services should still operate overall, but certain content-based aspects of the services may not work properly. In addition, turning off your browser’s cookies will prevent cookies from measuring the relevance and effectiveness of our services, e-mails, and advertising.

You can opt out of receiving Google Analytics cookies by following the instructions to change Ad Settings under the Google Analytics cookies subsection on the Safeguarding Your Data page located at <http://www.google.com/analytics/learn/privacy.html>.

Our site contains links to other websites, including those of our partners, whose information practices may be different from ours. Visitors should consult those other third party websites’ privacy notices, since those websites are not covered by this Privacy Policy and may follow different procedures. From time to time, we also partner with third parties who may place cookies on your browser when you visit our website, may send their own cookies to your cookie file, and may use those cookies to provide targeted advertising based on your interests and previous browsing history. Please note this does not opt you out of being served advertising. You will continue to receive generic ads.

We use Local Shared Objects such as HTML5, to store content information and preferences. Third parties with whom we partner to provide certain features on our website or to display advertising based upon your browsing activity also use HTML5 to collect and store information. Various browsers may offer their own management tools for removing HTML5.

The information above has been provided to give clear and comprehensive information about Nintex’s use of cookies and similar technologies. If you choose to use the Services without blocking or disabling cookies or opting out of these technologies, you will indicate your consent to our use (in accordance with this Privacy Policy) of any personal information that we collect using these technologies. If you do not consent to the use of these technologies, please be sure to block or disable them using your browser settings, the opt-out links above, or the settings on your mobile device.

## Mobile Analytics

Nintex uses mobile analytics software to allow us to better understand the functionality of our Mobile Software on your phone. This software may record information such as how often you use the application, the events that occur within the application, aggregated usage, performance data, and from where the application was downloaded. We do not link the information we store within the analytics software to any personally identifiable information you submit within the mobile application.

## Information Collected Through Nintex Live and the Workflow Platform

Nintex collects information under the direction of its Users and has no direct relationship with the individuals whose personal information it processes. Nintex works with its Users to help them provide notice to their customers concerning, the purpose for which personal information is collected. An individual who seeks access, or who seeks to correct, amend, or delete inaccurate data should direct his query to Nintex’s User (the data controller). If the User requests Nintex to remove the data, we will respond to their request within 30 days. If you are a customer of one of our Users and would no longer like to be contacted by that User, please contact them directly.

Nintex may transfer personal information to companies that help us provide our service. Transfers to subsequent third parties are covered by the provisions in this Policy regarding notice and choice and the service agreements with our Users. Nintex will retain personal data we process on behalf of our User for as long as needed to provide services to our Client. Nintex will retain and use this personal information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

## Nintex Customer Experience Program

Nintex delivers to our customers a world-class process automation platform experience.  We include in the development process for our products and services customer feedback received from usability tests, surveys, the collection of workflow statistics and user interviews.  The Nintex Customer Experience Program (NCEP) has been created to provide Nintex customers the opportunity to contribute to the continued evolution of Nintex platform.

The NCEP service will collect certain telemetry and workflow statistics to help us better understand how customers utilize the Nintex platform and where we might focus future product improvement initiatives. Participation in the program is strictly voluntary, and customers who have opted in can choose to opt out at any time.

The NCEIP service will run in Nintex products to collect certain telemetry and workflow statistics on a monthly basis. This data is then transferred securely to Nintex through HTTPS encrypted communications.   The data will be collected and processed without interrupting your use of the Nintex process automation platform.

The NCEP service collects only certain telemetry and workflow statistics and does not collect any data within a workflow or form. The data collected will include:

  * Nintex product versions installed (Forms and Workflow)
  * How often workflow actions are used
  * How often form controls are used
  * How often a form setting is used
  * Number of unique workflow initiators and approvers (Individuals are not identifiable)
  * Number of unique form designers and participants (Individuals are not identifiable)
  * What designer is used (Responsive or Classic)
  * What settings are used within a form; and
  * How often a form is used, designed, and submitted

This data will assist Nintex in identifying the platform capabilities customers use most often.

The NCEP service will not collect personally identifiable information,  SharePoint data (including documents, list items, calendar events, or search history), configuration data (such as connection details, data entered in configuration fields, or default values) or any data entered in forms by users.

All data is sent using HTTPS to ensure data is securely transferred. Data will only be accessible by authorized individuals and will not be shared with third-parties.

Any products that have the option to participate in NCEP will provide the option to opt-in or opt-out of the program at any time. This option will be available from the Central Administration site.

## Information Sharing

We will share your personal information with third parties only in the ways that are described in this Privacy Policy. We do not sell your personal information to third parties. We may disclose aggregate statistics about visitors to the Site in order to describe our services to prospective partners, sponsors and other reputable third parties and for other lawful purposes, but these statistics will include no personal information.

We may also disclose your personal information:

  * as required by law, such as to comply with a subpoena, or similar legal process
  * when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or respond to a government request,
  * to any other third party with your prior consent to do so.
  * if Nintex is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our Web site of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information,
  * to any other third party with your prior consent to do so.

We use service providers, including a customer relationship management software provider, marketing automation provider, social community software provider, gamification service provider, and website analytics provider, to provide certain services in support of the Site. These service providers may need to have access to your information in order to provide their services.

Certain services identified on this site are offered by business partners. If you wish to take up those services you will need to share your information with them in order to receive these services. These companies are authorized to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services to us.

## Public Forums

Our website offers publicly accessible community forums. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them.

## Social Media Features

Our website includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button, and Widgets, such as the Share This button or interactive mini-programs that run on our website. These Features may collect your Internet protocol address, which page you are visiting on our website, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our website. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy statement of the company providing it.

## Tell-A-Friend

If you choose to use our referral service to tell a friend about our site, we will ask you for your friend’s name and email address. We will automatically send your friend a one-time email inviting him or her to visit the site. Nintex stores this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email and tracking the success of our referral program.

Your friend may contact us at [inquiries@nintex.com](mailto:inquiries@nintex.com) to request that we remove this information from our database.

## Choice/Opt-Out

You may choose to stop receiving our newsletter or marketing emails by following the unsubscribe instructions included in these emails or you can contact us at [inquiries@nintex.com](mailto:inquiries@nintex.com).

## Testimonials

We display personal testimonials of satisfied customers on our site in addition to other endorsements. With your consent we may post your testimonial along with your name.

## Access to Personally Identifiable Information

Upon request, Nintex will provide you with information about whether we hold any of your personal information. In certain circumstances we may be required by law to retain your personal information, or may need to retain your personal information in order to continue providing a service. If your personal information changes, or if you no longer desire our service, you may update, amend, ask to have it removed from a public forum or testimonial on our site or deactivate it by emailing our Customer Support at [support@nintex.com](mailto:support@nintex.com) or by contacting us by telephone or postal mail at the contact information listed below. We will respond to your request to access within a reasonable time.

You have control of your privacy at all times, you may indicate who is able to see your information by logging into your account and updating your Privacy settings within the “Privacy” settings tab of your profile. You may revoke access to some or all of your information at any time.

Once you have created an account you may upload a photo of yourself. Please note that this photo may be viewable by other users of the site. You may, at any time, remove your photo by logging into your account and deleting it.

## Data Retention

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services contact us at [GDPR@nintex.com](mailto:GDPR@nintex.com). We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

## Links to Other Sites

You may access third party websites and services through this website. If you submit personal information to any of those sites, your information is governed by their privacy policies. These websites are not subject to Nintex’s Privacy Policy. You should review the Privacy Policy of each individual website you access via hyperlinks from this web site, and assess whether the policy of each website is satisfactory to you before you use that website.

## Data Storage and International Transfers

Information that you submit via the Site is held on servers in the USA, Ireland, and Australia. This information may be transferred to other countries, for example to other of our Nintex offices or where one of our service providers or partners is located in another country. If we transfer your information in this way, we will take steps to ensure that your privacy rights continue to be protected.

## Security

The security of your personal information is important to us. We follow generally accepted standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once it is received. If you have any questions about the security of your personal information, you can contact us at [inquiries@nintex.com](mailto:inquiries@nintex.com).

## Updating This Privacy Policy

We may update this Privacy Policy to reflect changes to our information practices. If we make any material changes we will notify you by email (sent to the e-mail address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on this Site prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

## Resolving Privacy Issues

Should you have any concerns regarding the Nintex Privacy Policy or you wish to access or update your information or raise any issues with Nintex, please contact us or by mail at the addresses below, and we will do our best to resolve your issues.

**Americas**

Nintex USA Inc.  
10800 NE 8th Street, Suite 400  
Bellevue, WA 98004  
Phone: [+1 (425) 324 2400](tel:+14253242400)  
Fax: [+1 (425) 458 0105](tel:14254580105)

1 Post, Suite 175  
Irvine, California 92618  
Phone: [+1 (949) 242-0455](tel:19492420455), option 1  
Toll Free: [+1 (877) 462-LOOP (5667)](tel:18774625667), option 2

**Europe**

Nintex UK Ltd  
Ground Floor  
138 Fetter Lane  
London, EC4A 1BT  
United Kingdom  
Phone: [+44 (0) 20 3693 0200](tel:4402036930200)  
Fax: [+44 (0) 20 3002 5613](tel:4402030025613)
